thehightechsociety.com 2019-09-19

# Privacy Policy - The High Tech Society

**Privacy Policy**

At The High Tech Society we not only respect your privacy concerns, but we also understand the issues behind them. We live in a world where information is a currency, and your private data might be sold by unscrupulous web-site owners looking to make a buck. In fact, most of our writers and admins have been a victim of this sort of data transfer at one point or another. That’s one of the reasons why we respect your privacy. Not only do we promise not to share or sell your private or anonymous information with anyone in any capacity other than site analytics, or the purpose for which you have given it, but we also promise to protect your information using the highest standards of web security. The following privacy policy applies to The High Tech Society and it’s sub-domains, newsletters, social pages, and other content.

 **What Information Does The Hi** **gh Tech Society Collect?**

The High Tech Society collects both personal and non-personal data.

 **Personal Data  **– We collect personal data such as email and IP addresses, your name, and other contact details when you voluntarily give it to us. This could be signing up for our newsletter, leaving a comment on one of our blog posts, liking or following one of our social pages, or sending us an email. When you do any of these things, you are voluntarily sharing your personal information. We do not use any of this data in any way except for how you intended us to use it when you sent it. So, if you send us an email, the only thing we will do with your data is reply to you. Or if you leave us a comment, we will not use your data in any way. We believe that your personal information is yours so we do not share it, or benefit in any way from it.

 **Anonymous Data**  – The High Tech Society automatically collects anonymous data for analytics purposes. This includes your location, computer and browser, your IP address if this is allowed by your browser, the length of time spent on the site, which pages you visit, your ISP (Internet Service Provider), and if applicable, how you accessed the site. This is for internal purposes only and is not shared in any way.

 **How Do We Protect Your Data?**

The High Tech Society uses the most recent web-security standards including Transport Layer Security, Secure File Transfer, and basic Data Encryption. In addition, any content that you give us, is protected by passwords and firewalls, so that only administrators of our website can access your data.

 **Cookies**

While The High Tech Society does not use cookies ourselves, some of our third party services do.

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners. You consent to our cookies if you continue to use this website.

Cookies are small text files that can be used by websites to make a user’s experience more efficient.

The law states that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site. For all other types of cookies we need your permission.

This site uses different types of cookies. Some cookies are placed by third party services that appear on our pages.

 **DoubleClick Dart Cookie:**  Google’s DoubleClick Dart Cookie enables Google ads (of which The High Tech Society has very few) to enable ads based on your previous website visits. These cookies are not associated with The High Tech Society, but you may opt out by visiting [http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Other Cookies that may be present on The High Tech Society include Java, Web Beacons, and any cookies from social sites or plugins that you use in your browser. None of these are related to The High Tech Society, but data collected may relate to your use of our website.

 **Social Media Privacy Policy:**

 **Facebook Comments**

 _We embed Facebook Comments plugin to allow you to leave comment at our website using your Facebook account. This plugin may collect your IP address, your web browser User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional tracking, and monitor your interaction with the commenting interface, including correlating your Facebook account with whatever action you take within the interface (such as “liking” someone’s comment, replying to other comments), if you are logged into Facebook. For more information about how this data may be used, please see Facebook’s data privacy policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update_

 **GooglePlus Comments**

 _We use GooglePlus Comments widget at our website for you to be able to comment at our webpages using your GooglePlus account. From this interaction Google automatically collects and store certain information in server logs like IP address, device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, in accordance with their data privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy_

 **Disqus Comments**

 _We use Disqus Comments widget at our website for you to be able to comment at our webpages using Disqus commenting system. Disqus may collect information about you when you register for and use the Service. Such information may include “Personally Identifiable Information” which means information that identifies you as an individual, such information may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, telephone number, username or account ID, and “Non-Personally Identifiable Information” which means information that does not identify you as an individual. Non-Personally Identifiable Information may include, but is not limited to, information about your browser, your IP address, device ID, what pages you visit on our Partner Sites, which website you came from, what advertisements you clicked on, whether on our Partner Websites, the Service or other third party websites, and other information about your online activity that does not identify you as an individual, in accordance with their data privacy policy:  https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy_

 **Facebook Comments Moderation**

 _We collect the data related to the Facebook Comment you post, only from   your consent that you grant before posting Facebook Comment at our website. This data includes your Facebook account name, unique Facebook account identifier, unique identifier associated to the posted Facebook comment, unique open graph object identifier of the webpage at which you posted the comment, unique identifier associated to the parent comment if you reply to an existing comment. This data is used to show recent Facebook Comments made all over our website and/or to show the old comments made at non-SSL webpages before we moved our website to SSL. You can revoke this consent at any time by sending us an email._

 **Facebook Comments Notifier**

 _We send the Facebook Comment you post, to page/post author and/or website administrator via automated email, only from your consent that you grant before posting Facebook Comment at our website. This data includes just the   Facebook comment posted by you._

 **Social Analytics for Sharing  **

 _We use Google Analytics to track social shares made at our website. Google automatically collect and store certain information in their server logs which includes device event information such as crashes, system activity, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL, cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your Google Account, in accordance with their data privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy_

 **Facebook Like,  Facebook Recommend, Facebook Share official buttons**

 _We embed a Facebook widget to allow you to see number of likes/shares/recommends and “like/share/recommend” our webpages. This widget may collect your IP address, your web browser User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional tracking, and monitor your interaction with the widget, including correlating your Facebook account with whatever action you take within the widget (such as “liking/sharing/recommending” our webpage), if you are logged in to Facebook. For more information about how this data may be used, please see Facebook’s data privacy policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update_

 **Twitter Tweet official button**

 _We use a Twitter Tweet widget at our website. As a result, our website makes requests to Twitter’s servers for you to be able to tweet our webpages using your Twitter account. These requests make your IP address visible to Twitter, who may use it in accordance with their data privacy policy: https://twitter.com/en/privacy#update_

 _We use a GooglePlus widget at our website. As a result, our website makes requests to Google’s servers for you to be able to share our webpages using your GooglePlus account. These requests make your IP address visible to Google, who may use it in accordance with their data privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy_

 _We use a Linkedin Share widget at our website to allow you to share our webpages on  Linkedin. These requests may track your IP address in accordance with their data privacy policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy_

 **Pinterest Save official button**

 _We use Pinterest Save widget at our website to allow you to pin images to Pinterest from our webpages. These requests may track your IP address in accordance with their data privacy policy:  https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy_

 **  Consent **

By using or accessing The High Tech Society you are agreeing to our privacy policy. While you may opt out of our policy at any time by sending us an email, we ask that you avoid our websites, social pages, and blogs if you do not agree with our privacy policy.

 **Contact Information**

For questions, comments, or more information, please contact us at info@thehightechsociety.com
